So you're thinking about laser hair removal and you're curious about some of the side effects.
My name is Keeley Selvage with Keeley's Skin Solutions and I've been a licensed clinical aesthetician for over a half a decade.
I'm going to talk to you about some of the side effects of laser hair removal.
For the most part, it's very safe.
It's a very effective way to get rid of that unwanted hair, but one thing you might want to think about is after the treatment, you might experience some redness, some swelling and some sensitivity.
So you want to make sure that you are avoiding the sun and really any hot temperatures.
Make sure your shower is maybe luke warm because it's just going to irritate the skin.
You could also break out a little bit in the area, and maybe even get some ingrown hairs because once those little hairs start to work their way out, they can just turn in in the skin.
It doesn't break the skin.
One thing you can do to help that is exfoliate ten days after the treatment.
Get a loofah and rub your body.
You should be good to go as far as that.
You also do run the risk of a slight bacterial infection.
If there's a small wound, maybe a small burn on the skin, your doctor can give you an anti-biotic.
That's no problem.
And you just keep it clean and take care of that.
Also if you have a history of herpes simplex, it can cause one.
So, see the physician.
Get an anti-viral medication prescription and again that should be good.
So, laser hair removal is very safe.
There's very few side effects and it's an excellent treatment.
I'm Keeley Selvage with Keeley's Skin Solution, and that is all about laser hair removal.